Guide to the William H. Potter Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Henry Potter Papers
1832-1933
MS 1047
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
Private journals, ledgers and scrapbooks kept by William H. Potter of Groton, Conn. and Brandon, Mississippi (1851-1955). The journals contain descriptions of his activities and discourses on religion and politics. A commonplace book (1837-1848) gives some information on his brief attendance at Yale and his stay at Bacon School. The papers contain an unidentified 1933 judicial diary and a Norwich, Conn. account book. The papers also contain a diary (1859-1861) and other materials of Kittie Potter.
Potter, William Henry, 1816-1887
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from D.E. Burnett, 1963.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Born in 1816, William H. Potter was a schoolteacher and insurance agent. He taught school for many years in Mystic River (part of Groton), Connecticut, circa 1840s-1860s and in Brandon, Mississippi, between 1851 and 1855. He then became an insurance agent around 1868. Potter represented Groton, Connecticut in the state legislature, beginning in 1869. He was an active Methodist. He died in 1887.
Scope and Contents
Private journals, ledgers and scrapbooks kept by William H. Potter of Groton, Conn. and Brandon, Mississippi (1851-1955). The journals contain descriptions of his activities and discourses on religion and politics. A commonplace book (1837-1848) gives some information on his brief attendance at Yale and his stay at Bacon School. The papers contain an unidentified 1933 judicial diary and a Norwich, Conn. account book. The papers also contain a diary (1859-1861) and other materials of Kittie Potter.
Education; Brandon (Miss.) -- History; Connecticut -- Social life and customs; Groton (Conn.) -- History; Mississippi -- Social life and customs; Southern States; United States -- Politics and government; Account books; Diaries; Albums (Books); Educators; Porter, Kittie; Potter, William Henry, 1816-1887; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  William H. Potter's journals contain descriptions of his activities and discourses on religious and political subjects. There is also a diary, 1859-1861, and other materials of (his daughter?) Kittie Potter and an unidentified judicial diary dated 1933. Potter's letters to Thomas E. Packer in the 1850s are in the Thomas E. Packer Papers, Manuscript Group No. 1010.
  - Private journals
    - 1832-1834, 1841-1848 (Box 1)
    - 1851 Jan-1861 Apr [includes diary, 1859-1861, and other materials of Kittie Potter] (Box 2)
    - 1860 Jan-1873 Jul (Box 3)
    - 1873 Jul-1877 Apr (Box 4)
    - 1877 Apr-1881 Jun (Box 5)
    - 1881 Jun-1885 Jan (Box 6)
    - 1885 Jan-1887 Mar (Box 7)
  - Commonplace book, 1837-1848 (Box 8)
  - Ledger, 1862 December-1864 Mar, 1863-1866 (Box 8)
  - Appointment book of court cases, 1933 (Box 8)
  - Investment book, 1907 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook of clippings, undated (Box 8)